<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>daily on Hello, There</title>
    <link>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/tags/daily/</link>
    <description>Recent content in daily on Hello, There</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 17:31:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jaeyo.github.io/en/tags/daily/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;The Presentation of Self in Everyday Life&gt; book review</title>
      <link>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/the-presentation-of-self-in-everyday-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 17:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/the-presentation-of-self-in-everyday-life/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a scene that happened early in my career that I still remember decades later. I was going about my business as usual when I suddenly heard a loud noise that made me look over my cubicle. I looked over the cubicle and saw the team leader of another development team in the next cubicle yelling furiously into his cell phone. I realized that he was on the phone with sales and that the development team was taking on unnecessary work because of sales&amp;rsquo; greed or mistakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching the movie &lt;Slam Dunk&gt;</title>
      <link>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/slam-dunk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/slam-dunk/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to see Slam Dunk for a while, but I thought that if I put it off any longer, I&amp;rsquo;d have to leave the theater, so I rushed to Dongtan Megabox to see it.
I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really expecting to be moved by it. I enjoyed the original comic, but it was just one of the many comics I read at the time. It was fun, but beyond that, my memory of it is hazy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The age of Stop-loss</title>
      <link>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/cut-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/cut-off/</guid>
      <description>Some keywords are born and come into vogue as a reflection of the times. Sometime in the 2000s, I remember the &amp;ldquo;well-being&amp;rdquo; era. The phrase &amp;ldquo;green light&amp;rdquo; came into vogue in the context of social changes that made it more comfortable to discuss gender and sexuality issues in the public sphere. In the era of tightening livelihoods, we saw the rise of &amp;ldquo;Hell-Joseon&amp;rdquo; and the rise of new words for new kinds of lifestyles, such as &amp;ldquo;YOLO&amp;rdquo;, which is a word for a new kind of lifestyle that cannot withstand &amp;ldquo;Hell-Joseon&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato chips and internet memes</title>
      <link>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/catching-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/catching-context/</guid>
      <description>I came across the article Potato Chips and Internet Memes in the newspaper and found it thought-provoking, so here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt.
&amp;hellip; The Internet, at least up to this point, favors fast and short information. The devices, the platforms, the mediums, the users. The phrase &amp;ldquo;fast and short&amp;rdquo; is a bit of a homophone, because in the internet world, information needs to be short to travel quickly.
However, knowledge is usually not short.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I met an old man who was lost.</title>
      <link>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/met-a-lost-old-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/met-a-lost-old-man/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I was waiting for a friend at a convenience store in my apartment. An elderly man walked in and suddenly said,
&amp;ldquo;Where is building 109?&amp;rdquo;
At first, I had to repeat myself a few times due to his inaccurate pronunciation. I soon realized that he was referring to building 109 in the apartment, so I turned on the map app and showed him the location. But after a while, he remained silent and asked again, &amp;ldquo;Where is building 109?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parents are the world to a child</title>
      <link>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/parents-are-everything-to-a-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/parents-are-everything-to-a-child/</guid>
      <description>The phrase &amp;ldquo;Parents are the world to a child&amp;rdquo; often runs through my head these days. When my child comes to me and pulls my arm to play, or cries loudly when she doesn&amp;rsquo;t get what she wants. I wonder if I&amp;rsquo;ve been neglecting my child because I&amp;rsquo;m a little tired or annoyed. A child can only eat what parent give them, and they can only play within the boundaries parent provide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday</title>
      <link>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 10:41:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/birthday/</guid>
      <description>There are days when the mind is unusually noisy. It&amp;rsquo;s a day like today. I&amp;rsquo;ve been drowning in a sea of work, waiting for something to happen, and then I look at the clock and realize it&amp;rsquo;s midnight. I turn off the lights in my deserted office and stumble out. Unfinished tasks buzz in my head like the sound of mosquitoes. I rub my temples, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help. At the intersection of Seolleung Station, I am lucky to find an empty taxi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting good people in good places</title>
      <link>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/meeting-good-people-at-good-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/meeting-good-people-at-good-place/</guid>
      <description>I saw this on someone&amp;rsquo;s Facebook and it resonated with me.
The reason everyone tells you to go to a good school, a good company, is to get a good guru. Quantum Leap is not just about physics, it&amp;rsquo;s not just about the growth of the company. It&amp;rsquo;s about people. To make Quantum Leap, it&amp;rsquo;s important to keep working hard, but it&amp;rsquo;s also important to think a lot and meet a lot of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I value myself</title>
      <link>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/the-value-that-i-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 13:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/the-value-that-i-value/</guid>
      <description>I watched a YouTube video called &amp;ldquo;희열의 순간&amp;rdquo;. It was a video with Ryu Si-min, and there were some interesting things in it. The part that stuck with me the most was &amp;ldquo;I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t care about what labels others put on me, but what meaning I give to my life is what matters.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s so obvious, but it&amp;rsquo;s something we often forget. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to compare ourselves to others, to line up our salaries, and to stick our necks out as if our company&amp;rsquo;s name value is our value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural images of the 20th century</title>
      <link>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/culture-image-of-20-century/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/culture-image-of-20-century/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a book called “Cultural Images of the 20th Century”. I picked it up for 2,000 won at a used bookstore I happened to stop by. The book was written by the now deceased writer Lee Sung-wook, and the preface calls him a “cultural engineer”. The essays in this book are an extension of that title. Most of the articles were written in the late 90s and published in 2004, and they are mostly interesting descriptions of the life, culture, and society of the time from the author&amp;rsquo;s point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of naming</title>
      <link>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/naming-is-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 01:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/naming-is-important/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a common saying among developers that they spend more time naming variables than they do developing. Naming variables isn&amp;rsquo;t that hard, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually quite difficult and important.
It happened the other day at a company meeting. We had an internal service called Alert Manager, and the idea of adding feature to that service came up. The idea was accepted, and as the discussion continued, the scope of the features we wanted to add broadened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to a new place</title>
      <link>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/move-to-another-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaeyo.github.io/en/move-to-another-place/</guid>
      <description>After living in Gwanak-gu for about two years, I decided to move to Yongin.
The reason I moved here in the first place,
because there is more infrastructure in Seoul Because my sister-in-law is close However, once I bought a car, none of this mattered much. Since I was always traveling by car on weekends and holidays, I started to go outside of Seoul more often than inside, and I started to enjoy the quiet and relaxing scenery rather than the crowded city.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
